<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://coffeeroastersco.com.au/blogs/resources.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://coffeeroastersco.com.au/blogs/resources"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://coffeeroastersco.com.au/blogs/resources.atom"/>
  <title>Coffee Roasters Collective - Resources</title>
  <updated>2021-06-29T11:34:17+10:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Coffee Roasters Collective</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://coffeeroastersco.com.au/blogs/resources/roasting-101</id>
    <published>2021-06-29T11:34:17+10:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-15T23:48:22+10:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://coffeeroastersco.com.au/blogs/resources/roasting-101"/>
    <title>Roasting 101</title>
    <author>
      <name>Marco Assanti</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left;"><em>Here is a great little article from the team at Ordermentum with their take on coffee roasting in the local market:</em></div>
<p class="">Australia is widely known for its laid-back style that goes hand-in-hand with its serious coffee culture. Currently, our coffee market is dominated by a growing number of specialty roasters and independent cafes. If you're playing in this space, we know how hard it can be to stand out in an industry with plenty of other businesses doing what you do. In today’s blog, we’ve collected some tips from top roasters around the country to help you succeed in the ever-competitive world of coffee roasting.</p>
<p class=""><strong><em>Be true to the coffee. - Gavin Gam, Aroma Coffee</em></strong></p>
<p class="">Gavin Gam, from 2014 Champion Australian Roaster Aroma Coffee, says that whilst their extensive tasting process is the key to their award-winning roast, it’s also important to value sustainability and be true to the coffee.</p>
<p class="">“Making the coffee isn’t just about money, it’s about giving back, paying a little extra and making sure the people who are producing the coffee are living a healthy sustainable life. If there’s love from origin, you can taste it, that’s the most important thing.”</p>
<p class="">Gam also notes how vital it is to use modern roasting practices and maintains that creating the perfect coffee roast is like alchemy. “You take the green beans and turn them into gold by combining modern heat transfer technology with traditional roasting practices” he adds.</p>
<p class="">Emily Raven who runs the roastery and café My Kingdom for a Horse loves sharing creative ideas with other people as she sees that as one of the best ways to stay ahead of future trends. She is always hungry to know what her peers are doing in their businesses so she can learn about current practices and anticipate the next trend in the industry.</p>
<p class=""><em>“Begin with a study programme and build a framework so you have a strong background to run your business,” says Emily. “Go out and meet people you respect and admire in the industry. You need to know what your peers are doing. Always look for something unique to give you the edge, and never stop researching.”</em></p>
<p class="">Sam Corra of popular ONA Coffee in Canberra also believes in the strength of constantly learning. One of his key pieces of advice is that roasters should surround themselves with knowledgeable individuals as it's the best way to learn.</p>
<p class="">The head roaster and the 2017 Australian Brewer’s Cup Champion also maintains that it’s important to utilise a good roasting machine. </p>
<p class=""><em>“Make sure that you’re working with good machinery that allows you to understand the roasting process. It’s like being a barista, if you don’t have a good machine with which you can control variables, then you can’t achieve what it is you want,” Sam says.</em></p>
<p class="">Standing out in a very competitive marketplace doesn’t only mean creating new blends, it also means providing great customer service.</p>
<p class=""><br>As Gabriel Tan, the head roaster and co-owner of the Western Australia-based Blacklist Coffee Roasters says, the key is to listen to your customer and work hard to exceed their expectations.</p>
<p class=""><em>“A lot of the time people focus on the technical side of things. I think that is really important but, personally, as someone who has worked the tools for a long long time, I feel that customer service is still number one,” he said.</em></p>
<p class="">Right now, Australia has over 1,000 coffee roasters, with new ones popping up all the time. Sure this means that the competition is tough but making a name in this flourishing industry is worth it in the long run. It’s also a friendly industry and there are plenty of people willing to give you help... if you ask for it!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://coffeeroastersco.com.au/blogs/resources/the-collective-is-here</id>
    <published>2021-06-29T11:34:17+10:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-15T23:48:29+10:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://coffeeroastersco.com.au/blogs/resources/the-collective-is-here"/>
    <title>The Collective Is Here…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Solomon</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="">It takes a wild mix of skills and just a little bit of risk for a Qantas aircraft engineer to reshape himself into a nationally recognised coffee entrepreneur - but that is just one of things that Rob Mergard has been able to tick off his bucket list.</p>
<p class="">Rob made the jump from the aviation sector over 20 years ago and has taken his small roasting business from start-up to national supplier in the years since.</p>
<p class="">But it is his latest venture which brings him the most satisfaction - helping other small to mid sized coffee roasters and hospitality start-ups get going.</p>
<p class="">“<em>We started back in 1999 with a single coffee cart in the Brisbane CBD. But as the coffee culture exploded in Australia we quickly realised that we needed the capacity and capability to service many different tastes and many different markets – and the only way to achieve this was to bring the best brands in the business together.</em></p>
<p class=""><em>We now send freshly roasted coffee beans around Australia (and soon into the US and Asia)  for our member companies and roasters, along with supplying cafes, restaurants and premium hospitality venues with coffee, machinery, training and expertise.”</em></p>
<p class="">The Coffee Roasters Collective operates from Ipswich and provides roasters with a chance to cut costs by using a shared machinery and production model. Business owners can either have their production needs covered under a contract roasting agreement or can source all their green beans at a substantial market discount and pay a small membership fee to use a fully kitted facility (with additional access to office space if needed).</p>
<p class=""><em>In Rob’s words…”Your goal should be to make it feel right for right now. Later will take care of itself. It always does.”</em></p>
<p class="">Contact one of the team at: rob@coffeeroastersco.com.au if you are interested in getting involved.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://coffeeroastersco.com.au/blogs/resources/a-truly-different-coffee-experience</id>
    <published>2021-06-29T11:34:05+10:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-29T17:21:24+10:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://coffeeroastersco.com.au/blogs/resources/a-truly-different-coffee-experience"/>
    <title>A truly different coffee experience…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Solomon</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="">As passionate foodies we are constantly looking at the international food and beverage space, admiring innovations and throwing our support behind the ideas that are pushing the whole sector forward.</p>
<p class="">The craft beer ecosystem has been one that we have had our eye on for a while.</p>
<p class="">What started as a boutique offering for a very particular niche customer has now launched itself into the mainstream and is building from strength to strength. A literal handful of non “big brand” lagers and ales used to be all that you could get in your local bottleshop, let alone being able to grab something on tap that wasn’t a household name out of CUB or Lion (not that there’s anything wrong with the big boys - they still make great beer!), but the entire space has now been turned on its head.</p>
<p class="">Launch back into today and the big boys are well and truly into craft offerings at this point because that beer type is dominating bottle shop shelf facings and a huge range of IPAs, specialty ales and limited run beers are taking up big real estate across Australian bar taps.</p>
<p class="">Why is this relevant for us as coffee roasters and for you as our customers? Because it reinforces the need for innovation, the shifting complexity of the Australian consumer palate and a want to marry a couple of our favourites - coffee and premium spirits.</p>
<p class="">So on that note we are pleased to announce the launch of Old Sea Dog (OSD).</p>
<p class="">This is one that has been in the works for a while and it has taken every second of that time to get it right. We were looking to create a coffee bean that held the experience of high end liquors without any residual alcohol and without tasting anything short of a perfect infused match.</p>
<p class="">So infuse we did - and the final product is better than we could have hoped.</p>
<p class="">There’s quite a bit to the process (and some of that is trade secret of course) but we’ve found a way to bring green beans and top shelf alcohols together. The beans we are using are 100% Arabica and from our own top shelf - then once integrated with a select spirit we age the product in oak and roast to a medium dark.</p>
<p class="">The first batches are ready for you to taste and we’re expecting this to be a must have around town in bars and restaurants.</p>
<p class="">The name “Old Sea Dog” is in honour of my old uncle Eric “Kanga” Kennedy. He was an incredible story teller and fisherman. One of my favourite stories from him ended with the punchline of <strong>“Old Sea Dog”</strong>.</p>
<p class="">“Kanga” was an instrumental support in the early days of starting our coffee business. So it seemed more than appropriate to name an alcohol infused product “Old Sea Dog” in his memory.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
